Contact

ty.lugtu@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/christinesantaularia-rn-bc-bsn-cmsrnb6377518a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Central Lines

Phlebotomy

Musculoskeletal System

Certifications

Certified Medical-Surgical Registered Nurse (CMSRN)

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers (BLS)

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support Experienced Provider (ACLS)

Registered Nurse

Honors-Awards

Ralph Parsons Nursing Excellence Award

The DAISY Award

Employee of the Month - Saperstein Critical Tower (3rd & 4th Floors) - 6 Times

Standing Ovations

Christine Santaularia, RN-BC, BSN, CMSRN

Clinical Nurse III at Cedars-Sinai Orange County, California Area

Summary

I've been a Registered Nurse for over 15 years, providing quality care and placing patient advocacy at the forefront of my day to day practice. I started my healthcare career as a Cardiac Monitor Technician while I was in Nursing School, and upon graduation I worked as a Registered Nurse at St Francis Hospital, in my home state of Georgia.

After a year of working in my hometown, I decided to challenge myself and signed up with a travel nursing agency which took me all over the country in many assignments, during which I developed what turned out to be an invaluable set of skills in the Nursing profession.

My travel nursing career ended when I picked an assignment at Cedars-Sinai, where I was recruited by my Unit Manager. I have been working in the Saperstein Critical Care Tower since, where I've had an amazing career surrounded by the best of the best in the healthcare industry.

Experience

Cedars-Sinai Clinical Nurse III January 2009 - Present (11 years 7 months)

- Provide pre- and post-operative nursing care for 3-4 patients with post open heart surgeries, heart and lungs transplants, heart catheterization, Trans-Aortic Valve Replacement (TAVR), appendectomy, stroke, CHF, COPD, DM, CAD, musculoskeletal injury conditions including lumbar Laminectomies.
- Educate patients and their families on disease processes; telemetry surgical procedures, medical-surgical procedures and other aspects of therapeutic regimens, including medication and pain management techniques.

Page 1 of 3

- Recommend and implement changes to the Medical unit regarding assignment delegation and prioritization, resulting in a higher standard of patient care. Reassessed and revised plan of care.
- Collaborate effectively with an interdisciplinary team of medical and health care professionals comprised of multiple physicians, nurse managers, dieticians, social workers, case managers, physical therapists, registered nurses, clinical partners, and technicians.
- Prioritize and delegate assignments, contributing to a higher standard of patient care and staff retention.
- Safely administer medications, and educate patients and their families on the proper use of braces, prosthetics, and orthopedic equipment with a focus on safety and pain management techniques.
- Provide care for patients pre- and post-dialysis, pre- and post-EGD/ colonoscopies, post-ER/MRCP, and pre- and post-surgeries.
- Provide a broad range of general nursing care services in areas of vital signs,
 EKG, phlebotomy, catheters, feeding tubes, IV and central lines.
- Monitor patients' PPT/INR levels to identify the need for anticoagulant therapy, and for potential side effects of medications demonstrating strong observation, assessment, and intervention skills.
- Administer all cardiac arrhythmia medications that require precise titrations.
- Review computerized laboratory test results.
- Continually precept inexperienced and experienced nurses (including travelers). Precepted over 25 Nurses.

Cross Country Staffing
Traveling Nurse
January 2006 - January 2009 (3 years 1 month)
United States

• Traveling nurse for 3+ years as a float pull, working for several agencies, in multiple Cities and States.

- Eight to sixteen weeks assignments.
- Telemetry/DOU/PCU/Float Pull

St Francis Hospital

4 years

Registered Nurse January 2005 - December 2005 (1 year) Columbus, Georgia Area

• Provided care to patients on cardiac specialty floor.

Cardiac Monitor Technician January 2002 - December 2004 (3 years) Columbus, Georgia Area

• Monitoring of cardiac arrhythmias.

I was a Cardiac Monitor Technician while I was going to Nursing School.

Education

Western Governors University
Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse